orangecoastcollege.edu 2018-06-30

# Privacy Policy

​​This Privacy Statement applies to official Orange Coast College ("OCC") websites only. Unofficial or individual websites of students, faculty, and staff should not request confidential and personally identifiable information from website visitors. 

We respect your privacy and are committed to the protection and security of your information. The following types of information may be requested of you as you visit our websites:

  * General information – including college history, interests, and hobbies 
  * Directory information – including name, address, phone number, and email address 
  * Personally identifiable information – including birthdate and driver's license number 
  * Confidential information – including social security number, credit card number, and college-wide ID 

Official websites of OCC are not intended for children under the age of 13. If a child under the age of 13 is interested in any OCC course or event, a parent or guardian must contact the appropriate department for information.

##  Information automatically collected:

When you browse through any website, certain information is automatically collected. Web servers collect non-personal information including:

  * Date and time of visit 
  * IP address of computer used 
  * Browser type and language 
  * Pages visited 

##  Usage of "Cookies":

A cookie is a piece of data that a website sends to your browser to recognize your computer. Our websites use cookies to help your browser keep track of your browsing session and to manage your preferences. It also helps the College understand web browsing and usage patterns. If you have configured your browser to reject all cookies, this may cause certain parts of the website to fail or function in unpredictable ways.

##  Personally provided information:

While visiting any OCC webpage, you may remain anonymous if desired. However, you may choose to provide us with personal information to fulfill the requirements of enrollment, make payments, subscribe to newsletters, etc. Information gathered is used solely for the use of communication and/or participation.

##  Release of information:

OCC does not sell, trade, or transfer personally identifiable or conf​idential information to outside parties. This does not include trusted third parties who assist OCC in operating our websites, conducting our business, or servicing you and your needs, so long as those parties agree with OCC in writing to keep this information confidential. ​

While certain records we maintain are protected by disclosure laws, OCC is required to disclose other records mandated by state and federal regulations.

##  Online accounts and passwords:

Our students and employees are given online accounts and create passwords that are unique to their accounts. Your passwords are designed to protect your account from unauthorized use. OCC is not responsible for lost, stolen, or otherwise disclosed passwords. OCC employees will never ask you for your password. If you have lost or forgotten your password, you can request that it be reset.

##  How we protect your information:

OCC protects your information by using technical, physical, and administrative security measures to reduce the risk of misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, or modification of information. Some of our safeguards include firewalls, data encryption, and physical access controls. When you transmit confidential information (such as a credit card number) through our website, we encrypt that information using the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol. 

##  Third Party Links:

While visiting our websites, you may encounter links to web pages and sites which are not owned or controlled by the College. Please be aware that no warranty or claim concerning services from these sites is implied or should be assumed. Third party sites have different policies regarding privacy (or no policies at all) and hence you should avoid entering personal information into such sites unless you have an independent and reasonable belief that these sites can be trusted.

##  Your Consent:

By using this site, you consent to our privacy policy. If changes are made to the privacy policy, revisions will be made here and the modification date above updated.
